thedeliberatemom.com 2017-10-06

# Privacy Policy - The Deliberate Mom

**Newsletter Signup**

If you sign up for The Deliberate Mom’s newsletter, we will use your name and e-mail address to send the newsletter to you through our newsletter service (Convertkit).You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time.

**Google Analytics**

Like many other Web sites, thedeliberatemom.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, country of residence, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

The Deliberate Mom site does NOT store the information collected by these programs in a separate database and it does NOT sell or give away this information. The information collected by these programs is not separately aggregated in any database with any personal information, such as your name, e-mail address, IP address, or specific location.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
This site uses cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on thedeliberatemom.com.
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to thedeliberatemom.com and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include…

  * Google Adsense
  * Commission Junction
  * Amazon

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on thedeliberatemom.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

The Deliberate Mom has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. thedeliberatemom.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

**Sponsored Links**

If you click on a third party advertisement (like an ad served by Google Ads) or an affiliate link on this site, and are taken to a third party’s website, that third party site may track information regarding your visit or collect the personal information that you submit. The Deliberate Mom does not have control over, or knowledge of, how or whether this occurs.

You should read that particular site’s privacy policy if you want to learn about how your information may be used.

**Privacy with Regards to Comment Submission, E-mail, and Social Media Contacts**

The information you submit in a comment to a post or by message to The Deliberate Mom (whether using our commenting system, the contact form, or direct e-mail) is NOT private or confidential. This information is public and is not protected. If you discuss your personal situation(s) through use of this site, in an e-mail, or by any one of our social media sites, please be aware that your statements and the facts contained therein are public.
